[{"question": "What is media used for?", "answer": "To transmit data over network"}, {"question": "What are the three types of media?", "answer": "Copper, fiber optic, and wireless"}, {"question": "What are the three types of copper media?", "answer": "Coaxial, twister pair, and serial"}, {"question": "Describe the build of an coaxial cable?", "answer": "center core --> insulator --> metallic shield --> braided metal shield --> plastic jacket"}, {"question": "Two types of tupes?", "answer": "RG - 6 : Cable company to homes\nRG - 59 : Used in homes"}, {"question": "Three types of coaxial connectors?", "answer": "Ftype - 3 screwed ends\nBNC - 2 ends\nSerial cable - for older networks - 9 or 25 pins. DB - 9 / DB -25 connector"}, {"question": "Describe a twisted pair", "answer": "8 insulated wires twisted in a pair"}, {"question": "list the types of twisted pair cabling. ", "answer": "Cat 3, 5, 5e, 6, 6a, 7, and 8"}, {"question": "describe the following of twisted pair cabling by category, stardard, bandwidth, and distance: Cat 3?", "answer": "Category: cat3, standard: 10BASE-T, bandwidth: 10MBPS, Distance: 100M"}, {"question": "describe the following of twisted pair cabling by category, stardard, bandwidth, and distance: Cat 5?", "answer": "category: cat5, standard: 100BASE-Tx, bandwith: 100, distance 100M"}, {"question": "describe the following of twisted pair cabling by category, stardard, bandwidth, and distance: Cat 5a?", "answer": "category: cat5a, standard: 1000BASE-T, bandwith: 1000, distance 100M"}, {"question": "describe the following of twisted pair cabling by category, stardard, bandwidth, and distance: Cat 6?", "answer": "category: cat6, standard: 1000BASE-T & 10GBase-T, bandwith: 1000 MBPS/10GBPS, distance 100M/55M"}, {"question": "describe the following of twisted pair cabling by category, stardard, bandwidth, and distance: Cat 6a?", "answer": "category: cat6a, standard: 10GBASE-T, bandwith: 10GBPS, distance 100M"}, {"question": "describe the following of twisted pair cabling by category, stardard, bandwidth, and distance: Cat 7?", "answer": "category: cat7, standard: 10GBASE-T, bandwith: 10GBPS, distance 100M"}, {"question": "describe the following of twisted pair cabling by category, stardard, bandwidth, and distance: Cat 8?", "answer": "category: cat8, standard: 40GBASE-T, bandwith: 40GBPS, distance 30M"}, {"question": "Whats another name for a patch cable? describe it.", "answer": "a straight through cable, contains exact same pinout on both ends of the cable. 56B typically used for straight through and inside of buildings. Used to connect a DTE to a DCE"}, {"question": "What is DTE and DCE used for.", "answer": "Data terminal equipment - endopoint devices thta connect to a piece of data communications equipment or DCE (laptops, desktops, servers, and routers). Data communications equipment - includes things like switches, modems, hubs, and bridges.  Used for straight through and crossover cables. "}, {"question": "A switch to switch connection requires what kind of cable. ", "answer": "A crossover cable."}, {"question": "What is MDIX?", "answer": "Medium Dependent Interface Crossover: A automated way to simulate a crossover cable connector even if using a straight through. "}, {"question": "What if switch does not support MDIX?", "answer": "you can use crossover cable"}, {"question": "How do you switch pins? or what pins do you switch?", "answer": "1 and 2 switch with 3 and 6 on both sides. "}, {"question": "What is a plenum cable used for?", "answer": "Ceilings, walls, raised floors, and air ducts places where wire is not visible. "}, {"question": "List the color order for a straight through cable. ", "answer": "orange/white, orange, green/white, blue, blue/white, green, brown/white, brown"}, {"question": "List the color order for a crossover cable with switched pins", "answer": "green/white, green, orange/white, blue, blue/white, orange, brown/white, brown"}, {"question": "List the tools used to build cable and their use. ", "answer": "end plugs\nwire stripper - strip outter cable to get to wires\ncrimper - cut cable\ncable tester - plugs into cable"}, {"question": "Describe a fiber optic cable", "answer": "uses light from LeD or laser to transmit information through a thin glass layer"}, {"question": "What are the types of fiber optic cable?", "answer": "SMF (yellow) - used for long distance and has small core (more expensive)\nMMF (orange) - short distance with larger core size (less expensive)"}, {"question": "list the connectors for a fiber optic cables. ", "answer": "SC (subscriber connector): stick and click\nST ( straight tip connector) stick and twist\nLC (lucent connector): love connector, 2 cables together\nMTRJ (mechanical transfer contact connector): connector for 2"}, {"question": "describe the connector on a SC and MTRJ fiber optic cable. ", "answer": "SC --> APC (Angled physical connector) - GREEN\nMTRJ --> UPC (Ultra physical connector) - BLUE"}, {"question": "What does WDM stand for and do in reference to fiber optic cables?", "answer": "Wavelength Division Multiplexing: combines multiple signals to one."}, {"question": "What are the 2 types of WDM Multiplexers, describe wavelength channels, channel distance, and speed. ", "answer": "Coarse WDM (CWDM): up to 18 channels, 20 nano meters, and up to 10GBPS (ethernet), 16 GBPS (Fiber)\nDense WDM (DWDM): up to 80 channels, 0.88 nano meters, and up to 8 Tbps (ethernet), 100Gbps/channel (fiber)"}, {"question": "What is the purpose of a transceiver?", "answer": "Converts media from one format to another, layer 1  to layer 1 conversion. "}, {"question": "What are the two types of transceivers?", "answer": "Bidirectional (half-duplex): Devices must take turns communicating.\nFull Duplex: Both devices able to communicate at the same time. "}, {"question": "List the types of transcievers. ", "answer": "GBIC - pluggable, can take in fiber or copper. \nSFP - up to 4.2 Gbps\nSFP+ - up to 16 Gbps\nQSFP (quad form factor pluggable): up to 40 Gbps\nQSFP + - up to 41.2 Gbps\nQSFP28 - up to 100 Gbps\nGSFP58 - up to 200 Gbps"}, {"question": "describe the concept of cable distribution.\n", "answer": "an organized system that connects the networks backbone in the MDF to the IDF and finally to the end users wall jacks. "}, {"question": "Describe the demarcation point in a cable distribution.", "answer": "where the internet providers connection ends and your network begins."}, {"question": "Describe the backbone switch in a cable distribution.", "answer": "Connects to everything on the network"}, {"question": "Describe the edge switches in a cable distribution.", "answer": "for larger networks, place on switch on every floor and connect to the backbone switch."}, {"question": "Describe the MDF in a cable distribution.", "answer": "Main distribution frame: A telecommunication closet which serves as the main starting point for all interior cabling. "}, {"question": "Describe the cable tray in a cable distribution.", "answer": "use to connect MDF to IDF. Unit(s) that form a system to securely support the cables and raceways."}, {"question": "Describe the IDF in a cable distribution.", "answer": "Contains an edge switch, patch panel, and other equipment to support the floor and nearest offices. "}, {"question": "What is a patch panel?", "answer": "Keeps data center organized by making it easy to move, add, or change cable distribution infrastructures. 2 sides - RJ Jacks & Punch downs. Connects fiber connection from one type to another. "}, {"question": "What tool can you use to test a network?", "answer": "A fox and hound or tone prober. Fox and hound use to test and scan a cable which allows probe to find correct label, and makes sound. \nToner prober used to find which port is tied to the patch panel. "}]